<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Zeeshan Khan</title><link>https://zkhan.in/</link><description>Recent content on Zeeshan Khan</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Nov 2021 21:48:41 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://zkhan.in/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Understanding Linux load average</title><link>https://zkhan.in/posts/understanding-linux-load-average/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Nov 2021 21:48:41 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://zkhan.in/posts/understanding-linux-load-average/</guid><description>&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; uptime 09:20:04 up 13:22, 5 users, load average: 0.11, 0.31, 0.42 Load average are those three number, its these to give and idea of how busy the system is.
It shows load for last 1, 5 and 15 mins, A common misconception is that it just shows how busy the CPU is, however it also takes other IO operation into consideration.
This blog post explains it beautifully what those three numbers mean</description></item><item><title>5 Years in IT sector (India)</title><link>https://zkhan.in/posts/draft/5yrs-in-indian-it-sector/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2020 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://zkhan.in/posts/draft/5yrs-in-indian-it-sector/</guid><description>I was an average student during my schooling. I somehow managed to survive long enough to get introduced to computer science subject in 11th, the subject was to teach C programming language, at first my mind start asking too many question, I told some of them to my teacher on which she said &amp;ldquo;Just accept what is being told this is the basic information that you will need to start thinking in C&amp;rdquo;, I absorbed few initial chapters and it started making sense once we got started with coding, I learnt few things, it started to feel like a super power I had, I can ask a computer to do something for me :), I was happy and eager to learn more but then session got over.</description></item><item><title>Setup your own E-book server Caliber</title><link>https://zkhan.in/posts/draft/setup_ebook_server_caliber/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2020 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://zkhan.in/posts/draft/setup_ebook_server_caliber/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Vuejs SEO without ssr using nginx</title><link>https://zkhan.in/posts/draft/vuejs_seo_without_ssr/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2020 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://zkhan.in/posts/draft/vuejs_seo_without_ssr/</guid><description>Vuejs was easy to get started with, so I picked it up for my new project idea was to finally compile into a single page application, completely static I was happy with the result, but SEO and link sharing was not working as expected, since all the dynamic data was pulled after but soon SEO became the requirement SSR was too much rework looked for alternative Nuxt was there but again that meant lot of rework and re-structuring then I thought why to filter the traffic from bots (mainly the platforms where the links were going to be shared) created a small flask app to handle that traffic and return proper meta tags added nginx config to send traffic to flask app based on user agents and voila!</description></item><item><title>Queue Implementation in C</title><link>https://zkhan.in/posts/draft/dynamic-queue/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Dec 2015 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://zkhan.in/posts/draft/dynamic-queue/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Stack Implementation in C</title><link>https://zkhan.in/posts/draft/dynamic-stack-in-c/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Dec 2015 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://zkhan.in/posts/draft/dynamic-stack-in-c/</guid><description>Typically stacks are like arrays, the difference is in a stack addition and deletion operations are performed from one end, this end is called top.
Let&amp;rsquo;s have a look at stack terminology
###Top A pointer to top most item is called top of the stack, all operations are performed on top of the stack.
###Push Pushing a item into stack means inserting a new item to the top of stack.</description></item><item><title>Doubly Linked List</title><link>https://zkhan.in/posts/draft/doubly-linked-list/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2015 08:04:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://zkhan.in/posts/draft/doubly-linked-list/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>